<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-15T23:26:04+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">nurture - Porter Robinson | Track-by-track Review</title><link href="/blog/2021/06/12/nurture_review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="nurture - Porter Robinson | Track-by-track Review" /><published>2021-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T23:26:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2021/06/12/nurture_review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2021/06/12/nurture_review.html">&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@mmattbtw&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@mmattbtw&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://mmatt.net/blog/2021/06/12/nurture_review.html&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;nurture - Porter Robinson | Track-by-track Review&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;A track-by-track review of the newly released sophomore album from Porter Robinson&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://mmatt.net/assets/images/nurture.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents-&quot;&gt;Table of Contents &lt;!-- omit in toc --&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#️-disclaimer-️&quot;&gt;‼️ Disclaimer ‼️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-the-layout-of-this-review-will-look-like&quot;&gt;What the layout of this review will look like.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-review&quot;&gt;The Review&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1-lifelike&quot;&gt;(1.) Lifelike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2-look-at-the-sky&quot;&gt;(2.) Look at the Sky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3-get-your-wish&quot;&gt;(3.) Get Your Wish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4-wind-tempos&quot;&gt;(4.) Wind Tempos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#5-musician&quot;&gt;(5.) Musician&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#6-do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do&quot;&gt;(6.) do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#7-mother&quot;&gt;(7.) Mother&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#8-dullscythe&quot;&gt;(8.) dullscythe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#9-sweet-time&quot;&gt;(9.) Sweet Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#10-mirror&quot;&gt;(10.) Mirror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#11-something-comforting&quot;&gt;(11.) Something Comforting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#12-blossom&quot;&gt;(12.) Blossom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#13-unfold&quot;&gt;(13.) Unfold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#14-trying-to-feel-alive&quot;&gt;(14.) Trying to Feel Alive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-i-score-reviews&quot;&gt;How I score reviews.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#score-and-final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Score and final thoughts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;️-disclaimer-️&quot;&gt;‼️ Disclaimer ‼️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a music reviewer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have a heavy bias towards because I have loved his previous projects (Worlds, and Virtual Self), so take all of this with a grain of salt, I just want to talk about Porter’s music, and how i feel about it, all on my own platform, so no one can stop me. &amp;gt;:) :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-the-layout-of-this-review-will-look-like&quot;&gt;What the layout of this review will look like.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to talk about each track, and how I enjoy/stuff about it from the artist themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Quotes that look like this”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;are lyrics&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Quotes that look like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are from someone’s mouth, in a statement. Not lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything else should just look standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurture (stylized as ‘nurture’ through most of the promotional art), is Porter Robinson’s sophomore album after 7 years since his EDM classic album “Worlds”. Revealed by Robinson on an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tcKAdFEQ_JU&quot; class=&quot;ext youtube&quot;&gt;aesthetic filled announcement video&lt;/a&gt; published on January 28, of 2020, it reveals the aesthetic we will see Porter use for the next year while hyping up the album. The then unreleased track “Mirror” playing in the background, really sets the tone in this video too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 16 months of anticipation, nurture released on April 23rd, 2021 through the Mom+Pop label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-review&quot;&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review is broken down and talks about all of the songs, then the last section will have a final score as well as talking about more thing about the album overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-lifelike&quot;&gt;(1.) Lifelike&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifelike is a beautiful piano intro that really sets the mood for nurture. It is (what I feel) is the perfect introduction to the album, and is a good choice to place it at track #1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-look-at-the-sky&quot;&gt;(2.) Look at the Sky&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the Sky an upbeat joyful, and some would describe “hopeful”, song. This song was revealed during &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4KGsgpFiswQ&quot; class=&quot;ext youtube&quot;&gt;Porter’s Secret Sky 2020 set&lt;/a&gt;, at the end. After fans begged and begged, this song released as a single on January 27, 2021. Porter said in the description of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PuMz4v5PYKc&quot; class=&quot;ext youtube&quot;&gt;Look at the Sky (Lyric Video)&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“i see ‘Look at the Sky’ as a mantra to remind myself that there’s good reason for hope, and that people can meaningfully improve themselves and the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see this throughout the entire song, with lyrics like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I’ll be alive next year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I can make something good, oh”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Shouldn’t it come to you naturally?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And everyone knows (Oh)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re losing your gift and it’s plain to see&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But then something must have changed in me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don’t fear it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now I’m sure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m sure”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see Porter portraying this message throughout the song. These lyrics can be applied to really anything in life, which makes the song very relatable to a lot of people. This song is a banger, that really grew on me ever since the single released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-get-your-wish&quot;&gt;(3.) Get Your Wish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Your Wish was the first single Porter released after announcing ‘nurture’. The music video showing him standing on a screen with water placed on top of it, and behind him being another large screen. (This being the setup for the recently revealed ‘nurture live’ stage) This was the first taste of how nurture was going to sound, and is an amazing song in my opinion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porterrobinson/status/1222580194248032258&quot; class=&quot;ext twitter&quot;&gt;In a Twitter post&lt;/a&gt;, Porter explains that Get Your Wish is about, “finding a reason to keep moving forward.” Porter then explains how during 2015 through 2017, Porter was doing really badly, and felt that his entire life revolved around music, and that for the first time in his music career, he was struggling to write new music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“When the glory tries to tempt you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It may seem like what you need&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if glory makes you happy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are you so broken up??”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love this song, the production on this is amazing making it a banger during the chorus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-wind-tempos&quot;&gt;(4.) Wind Tempos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the next track (Musician) came out as a single, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alivenextyear&quot; class=&quot;ext twitter&quot;&gt;@alivenextyear&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter replied, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porterrobinson/status/1367202814645178370&quot; class=&quot;ext twitter&quot;&gt;to Porter talking about how nurture needed an instrumental&lt;/a&gt;, saying, “oh cool so no instrumentals on the album.” Porter jokingly responded with this banger tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porterrobinson/status/1367203283203424260&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/MmmIyRw.png&quot; alt=&quot;This image shows Porter's Tweet replying &amp;quot;INCORRECTO&amp;quot; to @alivenextyear&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, what I’m trying to get at here is that Wind Tempos is the first instrumental track in the tracklist. Yes, this means that there is at least 1 more. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wind Tempos is a &lt;strong&gt;6 MINUTE&lt;/strong&gt; long instrumental track. This is the &lt;strong&gt;LONGEST&lt;/strong&gt; track on nurture. While you might think that I keep emphasizing this because I think it’s a bad thing, it’s quite the opposite actually! I really do enjoy this song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a very unique song, and &lt;em&gt;almost not&lt;/em&gt; an interlude. It’s not an interlude because of simply how long it is. However, it could be an interlude into the next track ‘Musician’, just because of the simplicity (yet complex composition) of the track. To say it’s a simple song, would simply be wrong. Wind Tempos is a very calm and soothing track, that really captures Nature at its finest. Just a great track in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-musician&quot;&gt;(5.) Musician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musician is the “last” single of nurture. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porterrobinson/status/1365378400286769158&quot; class=&quot;ext twitter&quot;&gt;Revealed on February 26, of 2021 in a tweet by Porter which teases the single’s music video in a split 6 second clip.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musician is about Porter’s struggles as a &lt;em&gt;Musician&lt;/em&gt; after trying to follow up his debut album “Worlds”. He talks about loving his past work, and wanting to create more music to be proud of, while also talking about not wanting to lose his love for music. This track also talks about subjects like burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musician also tackles Porter’s scary realization that he could quit what was helping him through tough times, that being music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lyrics like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“No, I don’t wanna lose it, this emotion”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I burn up, burn out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I shouldn’t do this to myself”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Then they say, ‘Fine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, do what you need to&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I don’t wanna see you wasting your life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now isn’t it time you get a job?’“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally &lt;strong&gt;LOVE&lt;/strong&gt; this song with a passion. The instrumental is AMAZING. With vocal chops from an unreleased Kero Kero Bonito x Porter Robinson collab. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/porterrobinson/status/1370086045711101956&quot; class=&quot;ext twitter&quot;&gt;Porter also demonstrated in a tweet on how he did it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “woo, yeah!” sample in the background is so good, and is permanently engrained in my mind when listening to this track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s really all I can say about this song, which is kind of surprising that I wouldn’t say more since I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.last.fm/user/mmattbtw/library/music/Porter+Robinson/_/Musician?date_preset=ALL&quot; class=&quot;ext other&quot;&gt;over 250+ plays of this song as I am writing this.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do&quot;&gt;(6.) do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While technically do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do (shortened to do-re-mi in this review) is a song with lyrics, the only lyrics being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“There’s too much I want to say, so&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All I want is said and done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to call it an instrumental track, because the majority of the song is, well, an instrumental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter has said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It feels like rollerblading through my neighbourhood—just feeling free and in this childlike state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and, I agree a ton! I feel like I could go out side with some headphones in, riding on my skateboard jamming out to this song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;do-re-mi is a great, fun, quirky, weird song. I love it a lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much to say about it, since its a short (feels short, is a 3 and a half minute song), sweet, &lt;em&gt;instrumental&lt;/em&gt; track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-mother&quot;&gt;(7.) Mother&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the tissues out, this song talks about your mother!!!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I wanted a song that expressed the love that I feel for my parents—as well as the grief of growing up. I felt like the minute I moved out, my youth would be over and I’d hardly ever see my family or dog again. In reality it wasn’t like that at all, I still see them all the time. But I wanted to capture the sad side of growing up—of realising your parents aren’t infallible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I couldn’t have said it better myself.
He executes showing the grief of growing up perfectly with this track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lyrics talk about moving out of your childhood bedroom, the love Porter feels for his parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production on this track really do fit the vibe for this song, and just the overall feeling for this song Porter was trying to achieve worked great with the instrumentals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also another thing is, sometimes throughout this song Porter has a weird british accent. I don’t know if this is just me hearing this, but it’s just something funny that I wanted to point out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much to say, but this song is near to my heart because like most of us &lt;em&gt;i love my mother&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-dullscythe&quot;&gt;(8.) dullscythe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The now 3rd instrumental on the album, dullscythe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… it’s the one track that doesn’t have a standard tempo. I wanted it to feel really hard and chaotic—something at the midway point to keep people on their toes—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure on how to comment on this track, you are just going to have to listen to it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/dangcj&quot; class=&quot;ext other&quot;&gt;dangcj&lt;/a&gt; under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Porter-robinson-dullscythe-lyrics&quot; class=&quot;ext other&quot;&gt;dullscythe Genius page&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;this would be a good explanation for this song&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“This song is about when you don’t know what should you do, so you press randomly and repeatly the music notes until you finally make a beautiful melody. The music notes are the choices you have in your life and when you finally find the purpose of your life, you can make a beautiful and harmonious melody with that choices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By: Kisuke Himari&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, yeah, that is a pretty good explanation for dullscythe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much to say, but my opinion on this track is that it’s a grower, and it grows hard, I love this track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-sweet-time&quot;&gt;(9.) Sweet Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SURPRISE!  Porter loves Rika! (Rika is Porter’s girlfriend.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song talks about Porter being so in love that, “you’re scared of dying.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This track definitely hits in the feels. Porter even said, “I was bawling my eyes out in the studio,” Which really, who wasn’t bawling when they heard this song for the first time. T-T&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production on this song is slow and steady, which really gives it the impact Porter was probably going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a great song overall, I don’t really know what else to say!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-mirror&quot;&gt;(10.) Mirror&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s that? Another nurture single? Yep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirror is the 3rd single that Porter dropped before the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirror is about Porter’s negative inner voice, and how being hard on yourself can end up doing more harm then good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter said in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0Jo-9aqhYc&quot;&gt;the song’s YouTube description&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mirror” is a song about the costs of being hard on yourself… It can be really liberating to recognize that most of the time, we’re only letting our own thoughts get in the way, and we can do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production on this snog is beautiful (as most things are in nurture), and kinda upbeat for such a sad/negative song (in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the choruses though, the song goes hard! I love the beat that Porter put on Mirror!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great song, great message, stop being hard on yourself!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Sometimes, the inner voice is encouraging, Calling for you to run those final few yards, You’re nearly there, keep going, keep going, keep going, keep going, It will all be okay in the end.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-something-comforting&quot;&gt;(11.) Something Comforting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANOTHER ONE, NURTURE SINGLE THAT IS!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something Comforting is the 2nd nurture single.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE DROP, THE DROP. THE DROP. ITS…. ITS SO GOOD, SO CATCHY, MY FAVORITE MUSIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANYWAYS YEAH, THIS SONG… IS A BANGER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production on this track goes crazy, the weird compressed (?) guitar strings, the drop again is amazing, the vocals sound great (as they do on most of the album).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song is simple, gets straight to the point, and is a banger. So literally nothing bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-blossom&quot;&gt;(12.) Blossom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PORTER LOVES RIKA, Part 2!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blossom is an acoustic guitar ballad from Porter to his girlfriend, Rika.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;was written in 1 night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hits in the feels, hard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;is so good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This track, again, talks about being scared of death, due to loving someone so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much joy does it fill you with to imagine somebody you love and care about really happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OMG THE PART WHERE HE TURNS OFF THE VOICE MANIPULATION AND SAYS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“it’s just that i love you”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AAAAAAAAA TEARS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this is a beautiful acoustic &lt;em&gt;poem&lt;/em&gt;, that Porter surprisingly pulls off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;13-unfold&quot;&gt;(13.) Unfold&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;featuring-totally-enormous-extinct-dinosaurs-&quot;&gt;Featuring Totally Enormous Extinct Dinosaurs &lt;!-- omit in toc --&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is the &lt;strong&gt;actual&lt;/strong&gt; final single of nurture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production on this track, is so good. Like amazing, perfect.
I don’t really know how to describe it, but it’s just so good. Definitely my favorite track off nurture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely, as Porter said an, “end of the album moment.”
This song closes out nurture with a &lt;strong&gt;BANG&lt;/strong&gt;! I can’t really describe how much I love this song, and how it sounds to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The production sounds like Porter and TEED are singing in the middle of a glitch, and it sounds amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The harsh sounds and all being the cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as Porter and TEED sounding amazing on this track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;14-trying-to-feel-alive&quot;&gt;(14.) Trying to Feel Alive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer, to nurture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song is a great closer.
In fact, I say &lt;strong&gt;it’s a better closer then Goodbye to a World&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song ends nurture with several questions like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Well, do you feel better now?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You climbed a mountain, are you satisfied?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This song’s production with the synth is, &lt;em&gt;chef’s kiss&lt;/em&gt;, amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is a &lt;strong&gt;true closer&lt;/strong&gt; to the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This song was me trying to make sense of the whole journey, trying to figure out what has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porter says this while talking about this track, and I think he really pulled it off with this track. He signaled this message perfectly through the production and just the lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple, complex, sweet, tear-jerker, closer to this amazing album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-score-reviews&quot;&gt;How I score reviews.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now since this is my first “music review”, I suppose I have to go into how I score these albums and such before I score nurture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 2 scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Out of 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 2 different scales that I use on different albums, smaller albums like EPs and some indie work I will only put under a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;out of 5&lt;/code&gt; review. Full LPs and other projects from major label artists will be put under both a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;out of 5&lt;/code&gt; score &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;out of 10&lt;/code&gt; score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most important thing is that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/5 does not equal 10/10!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/5 means it is GREAT, AMAZING you might say. However, I probably wouldn’t say it’s &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;, unless of course I specifically say it is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;score-and-final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Score and final thoughts.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Out of 5&lt;/code&gt;: 5/5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Out of 10&lt;/code&gt;: 10/10!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I truly think this album is &lt;strong&gt;PERFECT!&lt;/strong&gt;
I really don’t know how to describe my love with this album. I really just have a deep love with this album, and the upcoming live show. I love everything about it, the production, the lyrics, the meaning to all of it, is really good, and I love it lots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;remember, its just my opinion ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of when I said “Porter said this” came from &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/albums/Porter-robinson/Nurture&quot;&gt;the nurture Genius page&lt;/a&gt;, which sourced what &lt;a href=&quot;https://music.apple.com/us/album/nurture/1550626757&quot;&gt;Porter said on Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to set up Cool Channel Point Rewards</title><link href="/blog/2020/08/19/ChannelPoints.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to set up Cool Channel Point Rewards" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T23:26:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2020/08/19/ChannelPoints</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/08/19/ChannelPoints.html">&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:card&quot; content=&quot;summary&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:site&quot; content=&quot;@mmattbtw&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta name=&quot;twitter:creator&quot; content=&quot;@mmattbtw&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:url&quot; content=&quot;https://mmatt.net/blog/2020/08/19/ChannelPoints.html&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:title&quot; content=&quot;How to set up Cool Channel Point Rewards&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:description&quot; content=&quot;A guide on how to setup some Channel Point rewards&quot; /&gt;

&lt;meta property=&quot;og:image&quot; content=&quot;https://mmatt.net/assets/images/channelpoints.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;originally written: https://www.reddit.com/r/Twitch/comments/iw13xu/cool_channel_point_reward_ideas_and_how_to_set/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! I come to you with some Channel Point reward ideas, based on some of the ones on my personal channel. Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start I’m gonna leave a quick disclaimer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mmattbtw is NOT a developer, staff member, or affiliated in any means with these software / programs I (mmattbtw) uses in this guide, I am not responsible for anything going on with the development and progress of any of these programs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I have the emote pop ups on my screen using &lt;a href=&quot;https://overlays.thefyrewire.com/widgets/triggerfyre/&quot;&gt;Triggerfyre&lt;/a&gt; (you could also use &lt;a href=&quot;https://mixitupapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mix It Up&lt;/a&gt; however for my stream I used Triggerfyre.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To set it up, sign into &lt;a href=&quot;https://overlays.thefyrewire.com/widgets/triggerfyre/&quot;&gt;Triggerfyre&lt;/a&gt; and join thefyrewire’s Discord (to abide with r/Twitch’s rules, I can not link the server.) Once in there, follow the instructions in #updates, and then click on the header in #triggerfyre-beta. There you will find the instructions on how to setup the SE Overlay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you do that in SE and add the SE overlay into OBS (doesn’t matter if it’s Streamlabs OBS, or OBS Studio, should still work)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then head to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitch.tv/dashboard&quot;&gt;Twitch Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; then navigate to Community &amp;gt; Channel Points &amp;gt; Manage Rewards &amp;amp; Challenges. (note you do have to be at least a Twitch Affiliate to gain access to channel points at the moment.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once there, scroll down and click “Add New Custom Reward”. There, for my use of Triggerfyre, I have emotes that pop up on my screen, so in the name I would put the emote’s name, then add a cost, icon, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you are done setting that up on Twitch, you can head back over to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://overlays.thefyrewire.com/widgets/triggerfyre/&quot;&gt;Triggerfyre Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; and add an image. There you would put a command name, add the image, size, position, duration, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now make sure you click the dollar sign icon ($) and then add in your Channel Point reward name (case sensitive).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After that, refresh your SE Overlay and you should be done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second Channel Point reward that I have on my stream is automated Twitch things using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mixitupapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mix It Up&lt;/a&gt;. So things like putting the chat in Subscriber Only mode for a set amount of time, getting VIP in the channel, modding someone, unmodding someone, clearing the chat room, timing people out, ads, shout outs, chat messages, and even clips! However, for the sake of how long it would be to explain all of that, I am going to explain how to do something like automated Subscriber Only mode with Channel Points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://mixitupapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mix It Up&lt;/a&gt; and set it up with a bot account and a streamer account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the three lines on the top left, then click Channel Points.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then head to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitch.tv/dashboard&quot;&gt;Twitch Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; then navigate to Community &amp;gt; Channel Points &amp;gt; Manage Rewards &amp;amp; Challenges. (just like before!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once there, scroll down and click “Add New Custom Reward” (or for this purpose, Twitch already has a preset Channel Point reward for Emote Only Chat but we can change it to say “Subscriber Only Chat”, so you can add that by clicking “Visit the Collection”, then scrolling down to the “Twitch Related” section, click “Show More”, then add the “Emote Only Chat” one, after that edit it to say “Subscriber Only Chat”) Once created, adjust price, icon, name, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Head back to your Mix It Up app, and click the “Add Command” button, then click “Advanced Command”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under “Reward Name” copy and paste your exact Twitch Channel Point reward name (case sensitive).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next to where it says “Action:” click the drop down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here you will see all sorts of actions! (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SaviorXTanren/mixer-mixitup/wiki/Actions&quot;&gt;More information here on the Mix it Up wiki!&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since we are doing Subscriber Only Chat, we are going to need a “Chat Message”, so add that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again, since we are doing a Subscriber Only Chat reward, type in “/subscribers”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Floppy Disc Icon to save!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, if you just want it to turn on Subscriber Only Chat and thats it, well you are done! (if you want it to turn off subscriber only chat after a certain amount of time, see these steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a Wait action, and say how many seconds you want Sub Only chat to be on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add another chat message action, then type in “/subscribersoff”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the end, it look something similar to this (I added extra chat messages, and a really long wait time) https://i.imgur.com/l7ZnYTc.png&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Channel Point reward in my stream is “Tweets something on Matt’s account!”. I know, scary. But within moderation, is pretty cool. I would recommend making this reward a lot, and I mean &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;/strong&gt; of Channel Points, you don’t want some random troll to follow you, get 300 Channel Points, then tweet something bad on your account. Again, be careful with this one, and &lt;strong&gt;I WOULD NOT RECOMMEND USING THIS ON A WELL KNOWN ACCOUNT, MAYBE USE A SECOND TWITTER ACCOUNT&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyhow, disclaimer out of the way, let me show you how to make this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This uses the Mix it Up app again, so open that thing back up!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the three lines in the top right of the app, then click “Services”. Here you see a bunch of things you can connect to Mix it Up and play with, however we are going to focus on Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Twitter section, then connect the Twitter account you want the reward to post from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Head back to the Twitch Dashboard and make the reward with “Require Viewer to Enter Text” checked. [If you missed it, head to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitch.tv/dashboard&quot;&gt;Twitch Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; then navigate to Community &amp;gt; Channel Points &amp;gt; Manage Rewards &amp;amp; Challenges. (note you do have to be at least a Twitch Affiliate to gain access to channel points at the moment.). Once there, scroll down and click “Add New Custom Reward”. Then add a cost, name, icon, etc.]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go back to Mix it Up, and head back to the Channel Points tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the reward (case sensitive name!!!) then this time, add a “Twitter” action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the type click on the drop down, then click (Send Tweet).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After this we are going to use some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SaviorXTanren/mixer-mixitup/wiki/Channel-Points&quot;&gt;Channel Point Special Identifiers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the “Tweet Message” box, for the bare minimum type “$message” in the box and nothing else, however in my opinion, to play it safe, add who it was sent by and how. so something like “$message [sent via channel points, $username]”. ($message shows the message that they put in the message box on Twitch, then the username shows what username redeemed it.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it should look something like this https://i.imgur.com/ogiJnC9.png .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your community knows the bot can’t do @mentions on tweets (I would recommend putting that in the channel point reward description).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the final channel point reward, lets make a Text to Speech reward using Mix It Up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open up Mix it Up and go to the Services tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click Overlay &lt;strong&gt;Make sure Mix it Up is running before OBS, so the Overlay will work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy the “ http://localhost:8111/overlay “ onto a Browser Source into OBS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go back to Mix it Up, type in the name of the Browser Source that was in OBS, into Mix it Up, then click Connect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go back to the Twitch Dashboard and make the TTS reward with “Require Viewer to Enter Text” checked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Mix it Up, go to the Channel Points section, add a reward (case sensitive name D:««).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SaviorXTanren/mixer-mixitup/wiki/Actions#text-to-speech&quot;&gt;Text to Speech&lt;/a&gt; action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adjust the Text to Speech settings as you want, then type “$message” into the Speech Message box. (if you want you can also include $username to include the person who sent it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save the reward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refresh the browser source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it should look something like this https://i.imgur.com/Z4Bi8zb.png&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this isn’t all you can do with these tools, you can do a lot more and add your own flavor to the rewards. These tools are very powerful, so use them wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUUUUUGE SHOUT OUT TO THE DEVELOPERS OF THESE PROGRAMS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Program&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Developer&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Program Link&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Triggerfyre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/thefyrewire&quot;&gt;thefyrewire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;https://overlays.thefyrewire.com/widgets/triggerfyre/&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mix It Up&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/mixitupapp&quot;&gt;Mix it Up Twitch Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;https://mixitupapp.com/&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some useful links for Mix it Up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wiki: https://github.com/SaviorXTanren/mixer-mixitup/wiki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube:  https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcY0vKI9yqcMTgh8OzSnRSA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feature Backlog: https://trello.com/b/piWuuW4Y/feature-backlog&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any help I would Direct to these places for these programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Program&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Support Place&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Triggerfyre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.thefyrewire.com/&quot;&gt;Discord Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mix it Up&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mixitupapp.com/#contact&quot;&gt;Get in Touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also try to help as many people as I can in the comments, such as if you are having problem with something that I could fix, or if you want to see how I setup some other things, just let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>